all right
hello everyone uh
i'm just gonna wait a few seconds
um to make sure that you all are on
and if you can hear me uh
just give me a one in the chat
so i know that you are
i'm connecting so give me a one in the
chat if you can hear me
all right good there we go there we go
all right
so um i see you all are jumping on
uh i am not going to be staying on too
long as i said in
uh the um message i sent earlier
um for this live
i'm only going to be on about 10 minutes
y'all okay
i'm actually in texas right now so we
got some
uh
family things to take care of uh so i'm
just sneaking away
10 minutes at the most okay
um i want to share with you uh for those
of you that have been following photo
theology we're going to be looking at
something very specific today so we're
just going to go ahead and jump
right in so let me start by
um just talking a little bit about
you know how people see the bible
okay uh there are a lot of people that
are skeptical of the bible um
that think the bible has been corrupted
that the bible has been altered
um tammy i see you
um but that the bible has been altered
and they look at these contradictions
right or these so-called contradictions
uh in wording um you know
this account of the gospel says this and
this account of the gospel says that
and they write the bible off as a
man-made a book of contradictions etc
um so i'm going to share a story with
you that
some of you have heard before some of
you may not have heard before but
it's a story that i typically share when
when trying to explain the depth of the
bible
um do this real quick i remember um
long time ago um i was probably like in
my
i was in my late teens i was hanging out
in the mall with a bunch of my friends
and uh we were just walking around
hanging out
doing you know just hanging out i
remember seeing
a group of people that were really
mesmerized by something and it caught my
attention
so i kind of went over to where they
were and try to figure out what they
were doing and they were
like you know oohing and eye and just
like yo what
so i'm see what they're doing they're
looking at these pictures right
and these these pictures is just a whole
but it just looked like
zig zag lines just like a chaotic
painting and i started looking at them
like they're crazy like like
why are y'all getting so excited about
these pictures that don't make any sense
like it's just a bunch of zig-zag lines
and someone was like yo you got to do
this thing with your eyes
so i was like do this thing with my eyes
like
what thing what what are you talking
about and they started telling me you
got to focus it on this point and blah
blah so
eventually i start trying to do this
thing with my eyes right
and at a certain point i focus in on
this
one spot in the picture and suddenly
what appeared to be a bunch of zigzag
lines
turned into a 3d image i don't remember
exactly what it was that that the image
was of
but it blew my mind i was like what in
the world and i was getting
super excited about what i was seeing
okay
you do y'all know the kind of pictures
i'm talking about y'all probably have
seen them before yeah
so to a to a
to a degree the a lot of people read the
bible
and they don't understand how to
focus their eyes so when they're reading
the scriptures
all they see is guess what a bunch
of zigzag lines that's all they see
zig zag lines they see what appears to
be contradictions they see
things that oh that doesn't make sense
but they're not
understanding how to focus the eye
to see the divine pattern
of the scriptures okay so i'm just going
to give you
one example today one example today i'm
about to
juice down for you the entire
old testament now remember the bible
is made up of 66 books
written by 40 or so different
authors okay so there's no way there can
be collaboration between these authors
who lived at different times in
different periods
to um to create
such patterns in the bible
all right so what you're about to see
what i'm about to share with you
super quick we're about to juice down
the entire
old testament y'all i want you to listen
carefully okay i'm going to ask you
uh two questions
the first question is simply this
what are the offices
in the old testament what are the
offices
in the old testament
there are four offices in the old
testament what are they
i want to see if you can just put it in
the chat
what are the four offices found in the
old testament now for those of you who
are already in my photo theology class
i don't want you to put the answer okay
do not put the answer this is for those
of you
that are new to this um
that aren't in my class i'm asking the
question
what are the four offices of the old
testament okay very good kathy so
one office is judged all right there are
three more
offices what are the other
other offices there's priests very good
so there's judge
there's priest two more officers y'all
there's king very good and there's
prophets okay those are the four offices
of the old testament
there are kings there are judges there
are priests
there are prophets all right now you're
saying okay pastor
we get that what does that mean what's
the big deal well
my second question is in what
order are those offices emphasized
in the old testament that's my second
question in what order
are these offices emphasized in the old
testament
all right so what would be the first
major office the first
major focus right in terms of offices
um would it be the judges
no no i wouldn't be the judges that
doesn't come to later in the old
testament right
it wouldn't be the kings right israel
didn't get a king until
you know later in their history later in
the bible
so it wouldn't be kings it wouldn't be
judges it wouldn't be
priests it would be prophets
it would be prophets very good job so
prophets first right and we think of
joseph we think of noah
right we think of abraham um
these were all prophets right the the
first
major office or the first office to have
major emphasis in the scripture is
profit okay next what was the next
office and by the way that's all the
book of genesis right
so when we get to the book of exodus
what is the next
major office that we are introduced to
that has an emphasis very good i see
some of y'all are already
like uh jumping ahead i i'm seeing the
good answers right
priests right so the book of exodus
introduces the priesthood
very good so prophet and then priest
all right uh uh exodus the priesthood
leviticus numbers that's all dealing
with the priesthood now
what is the next major office
or emphasis in the scriptures after the
priesthood
come on yo and i already see the answers
in there
what is the next major office after the
priesthood
the judges right you got the book of
judges
very good so we've got prophets
and then priests and then judges
which means the last office would be the
office of
kings now one i'm going to say this
slowly up
please note the order of the offices
in the old testament this makes up the
entire old testament
prophets priests judges
kings prophets priests
judges kings now
i'm going to say this in the singular
prophet
priest
judge king
i i need to do that again i mean let me
say that again
prophet priest
judge king let me do it this way first
prophet then priest
then judge them
king y'all tell me
who is the entire old testament
testifying of
it is testifying of jesus
who came to this earth as a prophet
died was buried resurrected
and ascended into heaven to become our
priest
who before he returns again will
sit in judgment
and then come back as king of kings
and lord of lords give me your eight
if you're experiencing heartburn right
now
give me a in the chat if you're like
what
listen y'all this is the the format of
the entire old testament remember
this is not one man writing the old
testament saying
let me organize the old testament this
way to to
to make it fit no these are different
authors
over different periods of time that
lived and please
notice how they are without coordinating
with on another one
another why because they were all
operating under the same
holy spirit who is the design the divine
designer the entire old testament
is laying out the ministry of jesus
christ
first as prophet then as priest then
as judge then as king of kings and lord
of lords
and now i'm going to close at one point
one more point
i want you to notice this there were
many good
prophets there were some bad prophets
but many good prophets there were many
good priests
a few bad priests but many good priests
there were many good judges
some struggling judges but they were
good judges
when it comes to the kings almost
all the kings were almost all the kings
messed up
royally no pun intended
why why is that listen carefully all god
ordained for the prophets
to to in a sense foreshadow
the coming ultimate prophet jesus
god ordained for the priests
to reflect the role of jesus as priests
god ordained the judges to reflect
the role of jesus as judge however
god never ordained the kings
it was not his purpose for israel to
have a king
but they demanded a king it's as if god
was saying look you can reflect me as
prophet you can reflect me as priests
you can reflect me as judged
but you can't reflect me as king of
kings and lord of lords
and this is why the king's failed
miserably
to reflect jesus the true
king of kings and lord of lords
all right guys that's it what did we
just see we just saw the entire all
we just juice down the entire old
testament using what
photo theology simply by looking
at the entire old testament through
images remember
for many people the old testament is a
bunch of zig zag lines
it doesn't make sense what you know this
is here wise is here
what did we just do we just stepped back
we focused
our eyes on a particular point we
focused
on the picture of the entire old
testament and what did we see
we saw the picture of jesus as plain
as day you almost wonder when you see it
you can't
unsee it when you see it how do you turn
around and go back to zigzag lines
you now understand look when the skeptic
is talking about the bible
and oh look paul says this here and you
know
luke says this here huh you guys
y'all they are focusing on the words on
the page
not understanding that god's divine
design
goes deeper
goes deeper than a surface reading of
the scriptures okay
i'm done y'all i'm done i gotta run but
listen
the photo theology is six month
intensive
it begins august 11th there's the
website
if you all want to sign up for the class
and i strongly encourage you y'all
seriously it's going to be interactive
you're going to get to ask me questions
with this is a week
a six-month class every week for six
months i'm gonna be teaching you
the major principles of photo theology
so
i encourage you to sign up i encourage
you to sign up for this class
uh for this course uh it will
revolutionize the way
that you study the bible by the way that
one design i just shared with you for
the old testament that's just one
there are six other designs for the old
testament and the new testament
that you're going to learn in this class
so i encourage you once again
don't miss this y'all seriously
seriously it will revolutionize your
study of the word of god
okay with that said y'all i'm out peace
god bless you and uh i will see you
uh next week you know i'm doing these
these lives once a week for photo
theology basic for the facebook group
if y'all are not in the facebook group
go to the photo theology facebook group
and uh i'll get in that group and i'm
going live every week just sharing a
little
nook a little gem a little crumb
regarding photo theology okay so
blessings
and uh until next time y'all
stay safe